<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<koans>
	<koan>
		<text>A student asked Soen Nakagawa during a meditation retreat, "I am very discouraged. What should I do?"\n\nSoen replied, "Encourage others."</text>
		<source>Essential Zen</source>
	</koan>
	<koan>
		<text>Water which is too pure has no fish.</text>
		<source>Ts'ai Ken T'an</source>
	</koan>
	<koan>
		<text>What is the color of wind?</text>
		<source>Zen Koan</source>
	</koan>
	<koan>
		<text>Be master of mind rather than mastered by mind.</text>
		<source>Zen Koan</source>
	</koan>
	<koan>
		<text>When an ordinary man attains knowledge, he is a sage; when a sage attains understanding, he is an ordinary man.</text>
		<source>Zen Koan</source>
	</koan>
	<koan>
		<text>A monk asked Chao-chou, "I have just entered the monastery: please give me some guidance."\nChao-chou said, "Have you eaten your rice gruel?"\nThe monk said,"Yes, I've eaten."\nChao-chou said, "Then go wash your bowl."</text>
		<source>Zen Mondo</source>
	</koan>
</koans>

Nothing can match the strength of those whose lives have been shaped and forged through challenging and overcoming hardships. Such people fear nothing. The purpose of our Buddhist practice is to develop such strength and fortitude. To cultivate such an invincible core is in itself a victory. It is also the greatest benefit. Those who can succeed in this endeavor will savor unsurpassed happiness; they can manifest the supreme state of Buddhahood.

-Diasaku Ikeda

Dogen

   You should study not only that you become a mother when your child is born, but also that you become a child.

Then the Buddha denounces ritualism as a vain waste of time bound to lead to disappointment"

(Silabbata - paramasa)

Zen mind is not Zen mind. That is, if you are attached to Zen mind, then you have a problem, and your way is very narrow.

Throwing away Zen mind is correct Zen mind.

Only keep the question, "What is the best way of helping other people?"

Seung Sahn (Essential Zen )

A student asked Soen Nakagawa during a meditation retreat, "I am very discouraged. What should I do?"

Soen replied, "Encourage others."

(Essential Zen )

IF you're afraid of being grabbed by God, don't look at a wall.

Definitely don't sit still.

Jiyu Kennett (Essential Zen )

Once Yunmen said to the assembly:

"Medicine and disease cure each other. The entire earth is medicine. What is the self?"

(Essential Zen)

 Yasutani Roshi

    The fundamental delusion of humanity is to suppose that I am here and you are out there.
 Chuang-Tsu

   The purpose of a fishtrap is to catch fish, and when the fish are caught, the trap is forgotten.
   The purpose of a rabbit snare is to catch rabbits. When the rabbits are caught, the snare is forgotten.
   The purpose of words is to convey ideas. When the ideas are grasped, the words are forgotten.
    Where can I find a man who has forgotten words? He is the one I would like to talk to.
 Ts'ai Ken T'an

    Water which is too pure has no fish.
Zen Saying

    The one who is good at shooting does not hit the center of the target.
 Folk Zen Saying

    A heavy snowfall disappears into the sea. What silence!
Zen Saying

    Knock on the sky and listen to the sound!

 Zen Koan

    What is your face before your mother and father were born?
 Zen Koan

    When you can do nothing, what can you do?
 Zen Mondo

    A monk asked Chao-chou, "I have just entered the monastery: please give me some guidance."
    Chao-chou said, "Have you eaten your rice gruel?"
    The monk said,"Yes, I've eaten."
    Chao-chou said, "Then go wash your bowl."

 Robert M. Pirsig

   So the thing to do when working on a motorcycle, as in any other task,is to cultivate the peace of mind which does not separate one's self from one's surroundings. When that is done successfully, then everything else follows naturally. Peace of mind produces right values,right values produce right thoughts. Right thoughts produce right actions and right actions produce work which will be a material reflection for others to see of the serenity at the center of it all. 
 Zen Koan

    What is the color of wind?
 Zen Koan

   Two monks were arguing about the temple flag waving in teh wind. One said, "The flag moves." The other said, "The wind moves." They argued back and forth but could not agree. Hui-neng, the sixth Patriarch,said: "Gentlemen! It is not the flag that moves. It is not the wind that moves. It is your mind that moves." The two monks were struck with awe.
Zen Saying

    Be master of mind rather than mastered by mind.

 Zen Saying

   When an ordinary man attains knowledge, he is a sage; when a sage attains understanding, he is an ordinary man.
